Home
About

About F.A.Q.

Search

Search Search (Old) Random

Novels

Authors Titles Publishers Years Genres Groups

Serials

Periodicals Years

Statistics

Statistics Authorship Publishing Miscellaneous

References

Year Information At the Circulating Library

Titles published in the year 1866:

Henry Cadwallader Adams.  Balderscourt: or, Holiday Tales.  1 vol.  London: Routledge.William Harrison Ainsworth.  The Constable de Bourbon.  3 vol.  London: Chapman and Hall.Mrs. Alexander.  Which Shall it Be?.  3 vol.  London: Bentley. Anonymous.  Maitlands: A Tale of the Day.  3 vol.  London: T. C. Newby. Anonymous.  Man of his Day: A Novel.  3 vol.  London: Chapman and Hall. Anonymous.  Nora's Trial.  3 vol.  London: Hurst and Blackett. Anonymous.  Walter Blake's Heroine.  3 vol.  London: Hurst and Blackett. Anonymous.  James Meetwell: or, Incidents, Errors, and Experiences in the Life of a Scottish Merchant.  2 vol.  London: W. P. Nimmo.Francis Claudius Armstrong.  Our Blue Jackets, Afloat and Ashore: A Novel.  3 vol.  London: T. C. Newby.William Bainbridge.  Lionel Merval: A Novel.  3 vol.  London: Routledge.R. M. Ballantyne.  Shifting Winds: A Tough Yarn..  1 vol.  London: James Nisbet.M. M. Bell.  Doctor Weld: or, The Web of Life.  2 vol.  London: Frederick Warne.Matilda Barbara Betham-Edwards.  The Wild Flower of Ravensworth.  3 vol.  London: Hurst and Blackett.Caroline Ashurst Biggs.  The Master of Wingbourne: A Novel.  2 vol.  London: T. C. Newby.Albert Bitzius.  Wealth and Welfare.  2 vol.  London: Alexander Strahan.Richard Doddridge Blackmore.  Cradock Nowell: A Tale of the New Forest.  3 vol.  London: Chapman and Hall.Lady Blake.  The Wife's Error.  3 vol.  London: Hurst and Blackett.Margaret Blount.  A Broken Life: A Domestic Story.  1 vol.  London: Ward, Lock.G. Blunt.  Rose Sinclair: A Novel.  2 vol.  London: T. C. Newby.Mary Elizabeth Braddon.  The Lady's Mile.  3 vol.  London: Ward, Lock.Edward Bradley.  Mattins and Muttons: or, The Beauty of Brighton. A Love Story.  2 vol.  London: Sampson Low.Jane Octavia Brookfield.  Only George: A Story.  2 vol.  London: Chapman and Hall.Frances Browne.  The Hidden Sin: A Novel.  3 vol.  London: Bentley.Hannah Dorothy Burdon.  Uncle Armstrong: A Narrative.  3 vol.  London: T. C. Newby.Henry John Wilmot Buxton.  The Mysteries of Isis: or, The College Life of Paul Romaine. A Story of Oxford.  1 vol.  London: Ward, Lock.Lady Pamela Campbell.  A Woman's Confession.  3 vol.  London: Hurst and Blackett.Elizabeth Rundle Charles.  Winifred Bertram and the World She Lived in.  1 vol.  Edinburgh: Nelson and Sons.Clara de Chatelain.  The Sedan-Chair, and Sir Wilfred's Seven Flights.  1 vol.  London: Routledge.Julie Bosville Chetwynd.  Three Hundred a Year: A Novel.  2 vol.  London: Tinsley Brothers.Henry Fothergill Chorley.  A Prodigy: A Tale of Music.  3 vol.  London: Chapman and Hall.Wilkie Collins.  Armadale.  2 vol.  London: Smith, Elder.Charles Allston Collins.  At the Bar: A Tale.  2 vol.  London: Chapman and Hall.George Hatton Colomb.  The Shadows of Destiny: A Romance.  2 vol.  London: Chapman and Hall.Dinah Marie Craik.  A Noble Life.  2 vol.  London: Hurst and Blackett.Camilla Dufour Crosland.  The Island of the Rainbow: A Fairy Tale and Other Fancies.  1 vol.  London: Routledge.William Cyples.  Philip the Dreamer.  3 vol.  London: T. C. Newby.Elizabeth Daniel.  Grasping at Shadows.  3 vol.  London: Skeet.Edward William Lewis Davies.  Paul Pendril: or, Sport and Adventure in Corsica.  1 vol.  London: Bentley.F. Devonshire.  Emily Foinder: or, The See-Saw of Life. A Novel.  3 vol.  London: Tinsley Brothers.Louisa June Campbell Downes.  Thrice His: "His to guard, to serve, to save!" A Tale.  2 vol.  London: Bentley.Anna Harriet Drury.  The Three Half-Crowns: A Story for Boys.  1 vol.  London: S.P.C.K..Henry Sutherland Edwards.  The Three Louisas: A Novel.  3 vol.  London: Tinsley Brothers.Annie Edwards.  Archie Lovell.  3 vol.  London: Chapman and Hall.George Eliot.  Felix Holt, the Radical.  3 vol.  Edinburgh: Blackwood.George Manville Fenn.  Hollowdell Grange: or, Holiday Hours in a Country Home.  1 vol.  London: Routledge.Percy H. Fitzgerald.  Jenny Bell: A Story.  3 vol.  London: Bentley.Percy H. Fitzgerald.  The Second Mrs. Tillotson: A Story.  3 vol.  London: Tinsley Brothers.Mark Francis.  No Easy Task.  2 vol.  London: Skeet.Elizabeth Cleghorn Gaskell.  Wives and Daughters: An Everyday Story.  2 vol.  London: Smith, Elder. George.  The State Coach and the Disaffected Van: A Tale of Serious Sport..  2 vol.  London: T. C. Newby.Agnes Giberne.  Linda.  1 vol.  London: S.P.C.K..Mary Ann Danet Gifford.  King's Baynard.  3 vol.  London: Hurst and Blackett.William Gilbert.  Doctor Austin's Guests.  2 vol.  London: Alexander Strahan.William Gilbert.  The Magic Mirror: A Round of Tales for Young and Old.  1 vol.  London: Alexander Strahan.James Greenwood.  Silas the Conjuror: His Travels and Perils.  1 vol.  London: Ward, Lock.James Greenwood.  The True History of a Little Ragamuffin.  1 vol.  London: Ward, Lock.James Greenwood.  The Hatchet Throwers.  1 vol.  London: J. C. Hotten.Cecil Griffith.  Victory Deane: A Novel.  3 vol.  London: Saunders and Otley.Charlotte Hardcastle.  A Troubled Stream: A Story.  3 vol.  London: T. C. Newby.Lady Duffus Hardy.  A Casual Acquaintance: A Novel, Founded on Fact.  2 vol.  London: Sampson Low.Isabella Neil Harwood.  Carleton Grange: A Novel.  3 vol.  London: Tinsley Brothers.John Berwick Harwood.  Major Peter.  3 vol.  London: Bentley.John Berwick Harwood.  Plain John Orpington.  3 vol.  London: Bentley.Joseph Hatton.  Against the Stream.  3 vol.  London: T. C. Newby.Matilda Mary Hays.  Adrienne Hope: The Story of a Life.  2 vol.  London: T. C. Newby.Henry Holl.  White Favour: A Novel.  3 vol.  London: Sampson Low.Dora Hort.  Hena: or, Life in Tahiti.  2 vol.  London: Saunders and Otley.Victor Hugo.  Toilers of the Sea.  3 vol.  London: Sampson Low.Henry Jackson.  Gilbert Rugge.  3 vol.  London: Hurst and Blackett.Sarah Anne Jeffreys.  Maggie Lynne: A Novel.  3 vol.  London: T. C. Newby.Annie Keary.  Clemency Franklyn.  2 vol.  London: Macmillan.Henrietta Keddie.  Days of Yore.  2 vol.  London: Alexander Strahan.Henrietta Keddie.  Sweet Counsel: A Book for Girls.  1 vol.  London: Frederick Warne.Ellinor J. Kelly.  Fetching and Keeping.  1 vol.  London: S.P.C.K..Miles Gerald Keon.  Dion and the Sibyls: A Romance of the First Century.  2 vol.  London: Bentley.Henry Kingsley.  Leighton Court: A Country House Story.  2 vol.  London: Macmillan.Charles Kingsley.  Hereward, the Last of the English.  2 vol.  London: Macmillan.William Henry Giles Kingston.  Mountain Moggy: or, The Stoning of the Witch. A Tale for the Young.  1 vol.  London: S.P.C.K..George Alfred Lawrence.  Sans Merci: or, Kestrels and Falcons.  3 vol.  London: Tinsley Brothers.J. Sheridan Le Fanu.  All in the Dark.  2 vol.  London: Bentley.Mark Lemon.  Falkner Lyle: or, The Story of Two Wives.  3 vol.  London: Hurst and Blackett.Charles Lever.  Sir Brook Fossbrooke.  3 vol.  Edinburgh: Blackwood.Eliza Lynn Linton.  Lizzie Lorton of Greyrigg.  3 vol.  London: Tinsley Brothers.Arthur Locker.  Sweet Seventeen.  3 vol.  London: Chapman and Hall.George Macaulay.  Hetty Gouldworth: A Novel.  2 vol.  London: T. C. Newby.George MacDonald.  Annals of a Quiet Neighbourhood.  3 vol.  London: Alexander Strahan.Matilda Anne Mackarness.  The Naughty Girl of the Family.  1 vol.  London: Routledge.Florence Marryat.  For Ever and Ever: A Drama of Life.  3 vol.  London: Bentley.Emma Marshall.  Millicent Legh: A Tale.  1 vol.  London: Seeley.Janet Maughan.  The Co-Heiress: A Novel.  3 vol.  London: Tinsley Brothers.Janet Maughan.  The Man of Mark.  3 vol.  London: Tinsley Brothers.Justin McCarthy.  Paul Massie: A Romance.  3 vol.  London: Tinsley Brothers.Elizabeth Thomasina Meade.  Ashton Morton: or, Memories of my Life.  1 vol.  London: T. C. Newby.George Meredith.  Vittoria.  3 vol.  London: Chapman and Hall.George Mills.  The Beggar's Benison: or, A Hero, without a name; but, with an aim. A Clydesdale Story.  2 vol.  London: Cassell.Donald Grant Mitchell.  Doctor Johns: Being a Narrative of Certain Events in the Life of an Orthodox Minister of Connecticut.  2 vol.  London: Sampson Low.Luise Mühlbach.  Romance of a Court: or, Sans Souci; from the German.  3 vol.  London: Bentley.Emma Newby.  Trodden Down: A Novel.  3 vol.  London: T. C. Newby.Caroline Elizabeth Okeden.  Felicia's Dowry.  3 vol.  London: Hurst and Blackett.Margaret Oliphant.  Miss Marjoribanks.  3 vol.  Edinburgh: Blackwood.Margaret Oliphant.  Madonna Mary: A Story of Modern English Life.  3 vol.  London: Hurst and Blackett.Margaret Oliphant.  A Son of the Soil.  2 vol.  London: Macmillan. Ouida.  Chandos: A Novel.  3 vol.  London: Chapman and Hall.Susanna Mary Paull.  Lucy West: or, The Orphans of Highcliff.  1 vol.  London: Frederick Warne.James Payn.  Mirk Abbey.  3 vol.  London: Hurst and Blackett.Mrs. Pemberton.  Dacia Singleton.  3 vol.  London: Tinsley Brothers.Mrs. Pemberton.  What Money Can't Do: A Novel.  3 vol.  London: Tinsley Brothers.Rose Macqueen Piddington.  The Gain of a Loss: A Novel.  3 vol.  London: T. C. Newby.William Platt.  Angelo Lyons.  3 vol.  London: Saunders and Otley.Lady Emily Ponsonby.  Sir Owen Fairfax.  3 vol.  London: Hurst and Blackett.Elizabeth P. Ramsay.  Social Life in Sydney: or, Colonial Experience. An Australian Tale.  1 vol.  Edinburgh: R. Grant and Son.Charles Reade.  Griffith Gaunt: or, Jealousy.  3 vol.  London: Chapman and Hall.Capt. Mayne Reid.  The Headless Horseman: A Strange Tale of Texas.  2 vol.  London: C. H. Clarke.Charlotte Elizabeth Riddell.  Phemie Keller: A Novel.  3 vol.  London: Tinsley Brothers.Anne J. Robertson.  The Story of Nelly Dillon.  2 vol.  London: T. C. Newby.Frederick William Robinson.  Beyond the Church.  3 vol.  London: Hurst and Blackett.Frederick William Robinson.  Christie's Faith.  3 vol.  London: Hurst and Blackett.Frederick William Robinson.  Prison Characters Drawn from Life, by a Prison Matron.  2 vol.  London: Hurst and Blackett.John Saunders.  Bound to the Wheel.  3 vol.  London: Hurst and Blackett.Hon. Charles Stuart Savile.  Beating to Windward: or, Light and Shadow.  3 vol.  London: T. C. Newby.Carl Henrik Scharling.  Noddebo Parsonage: Country Life in Denmark.  2 vol.  London: Bentley.Frederick Sheridan.  Shot!: or, The Ghost's Seat at Deymont.  2 vol.  London: T. C. Newby.Felicia Mary Frances Skene.  Hidden Depths.  2 vol.  Edinburgh: Edmonston and Douglas.John Edwin Hilary Skinner.  After the Storm: or, Jonathan and his Neighbours.  2 vol.  London: Bentley.Menella Bute Smedley.  Twice Lost, and Other Tales.  1 vol.  London: Virtue.Alexander Smith.  Alfred Hagart's Household.  2 vol.  London: Alexander Strahan.Emily Spender.  Kingsford: A Novel.  2 vol.  London: Hurst and Blackett.Eliza Tabor Stephenson.  Hester's Sacrifice.  3 vol.  London: Hurst and Blackett.Eliza Tabor Stephenson.  Rachel's Secret.  3 vol.  London: Hurst and Blackett.Julia Cecilia Stretton.  Lords and Ladies.  3 vol.  London: Hurst and Blackett.Hesba Stretton.  Clives of Burcot.  3 vol.  London: Tinsley Brothers.Hesba Stretton.  The Fishers of Derby Haven.  1 vol.  London: R.T.S..Thomas Sutton.  Unconventional: A Novel.  3 vol.  London: Sampson Low.Bayard Taylor.  The Story of Kennett.  2 vol.  London: Sampson Low.Annie Thomas.  Played Out: A Novel.  3 vol.  London: Chapman and Hall.Annie Thomas.  Walter Goring.  3 vol.  London: Chapman and Hall.Walter Thornbury.  Greatheart.  3 vol.  London: Hurst and Blackett.Anthony Trollope.  The Belton Estate.  3 vol.  London: Chapman and Hall.Frank Trollope.  Old Man's Secret.  3 vol.  London: T. C. Newby.Thomas Adolphus Trollope.  Gemma: A Novel.  3 vol.  London: Chapman and Hall.Frances Eleanor Trollope.  Aunt Margaret's Troubles.  1 vol.  London: Chapman and Hall.Hannah Maria Whitehead.  The Grahames of Bessbridge House, Dydborough.  2 vol.  London: Chapman and Hall.S. Russell Whitney.  Mother's Favourite.  3 vol.  London: Hurst and Blackett.George John Whyte-Melville.  Cerise: A Tale of the Last Century.  3 vol.  London: Chapman and Hall.Lady Emma Caroline Wood.  Rosewarne.  3 vol.  London: Chapman and Hall.Ellen Wood.  Elster's Folly: A Novel.  3 vol.  London: Tinsley Brothers.Ellen Wood.  St. Martin's Eve.  3 vol.  London: Tinsley Brothers.Emma Jane Worboise.  St. Beetha's: or, The Heiress of Arne.  1 vol.  London: Jackson, Walford and Hodder.Emma Jane Worboise.  Sir Julian's Wife.  1 vol.  London: Virtue.Emma Jane Worboise.  Violet Vaughan: or, The Shadows of Warneford.  1 vol.  London: James Clarke.Sir Lascelles Wraxall.  Fides: or, The Beauty of Mayence. Adapted from the German.  3 vol.  London: Hurst and Blackett.Edmund Hodgson Yates.  Kissing the Rod: A Novel.  3 vol.  London: Tinsley Brothers.Edmund Hodgson Yates.  Land at Last: A Novel in Three Books.  3 vol.  London: Chapman and Hall.Charlotte Mary Yonge.  The Dove in the Eagle's Nest.  2 vol.  London: Macmillan.Charlotte Mary Yonge.  The Prince and the Page: A Story of the Last Crusade.  1 vol.  London: Macmillan.

© 2018 Troy J. Bassett | Contact: bassettt@ipfw.edu | Last Updated: 1 January 2018